<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bed010.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.1">The translation of SmartKom to english is in its final stages.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.2">The synthesis module will be the last one to do, after the english syntax trees are completed.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.3">The system is still buggy and unstable, but it will soon be ready for a demonstration.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.4">This is the first of two working demos required for the project.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.5">Further than that, there are no restrictions on the focus of the research or its possible applications.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.6">For example, issues like spatial descriptions could be investigated.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.7">The variety of linguistic conventions seem to develop around an ego/allo-centric and a proximal/distal paradigm.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.8">The latter is also reflected in neuro-physiological data.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.9">From an engineering perspective, the belief-net for the AVE task should be completed within a few weeks.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.10">The majority of the nodes are already there.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.11">This leaves the dependencies between them and the rules of computation to be set.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.12">Since the whole system is going to be re-designed, there are major decisions to be taken regarding the parser and the ontology, as well as what can be re-used from past EML projects.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.13">In parallel, another team is working on formalisation and notation.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.14">Finally, more ideas are expected to come from students and their research.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bed010.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.15">The final english SmartKom demo will be presented to the whole institute once the system is de-bugged and stabilised.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.16">After the demo, the focus of research can switch towards purely scientific goals, including issues on ontology, deep semantic constructions, execution engines etc.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.17">Moreover, a new system will be designed for the project and at least some parts of it should be built.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.18">Similarly, the construction analyser should be a single, general tool working for both the tourist domain and child language modelling.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.19">The focus for the next meeting will be on the belief-net, of which a working demo should be complete in the next few weeks.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.20">Since there are not enough data, its connections and weights will have to be designed.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.21">Although JavaBayes has been the tool of choice until now, the possibility that Hugin could be a better option should be investigated.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.22">In order to promote the collaboration with EML, the group-ware server there will be updated with all progress being made in the two sites.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.23">A talk on some of the issues will also be organised to take place at DFKI.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bed010.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.24">The german SmartKom version available on the server does not work.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.25">The english version, although still under development, does work, however, the system is still unstable as -apart from other reasons- it was initially built to work with a touch screen.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.26">De-bugging and cleaning up has to take place before any new modules are added on it.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.27">As regards the belief-net, no connections and dependencies have been built into it.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.28">These will have to be guessed instead of learnt through data, as not enough data is available for such a task.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.29">Finally, it has been noted that the JavaBayes GUI does not satisfy all the presentation requirements for this belief-net and modifying the underlying code would be too time-consuming.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bed010.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.30">The german SmartKom system has been translated to English up to the speech synthesis level.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.31">The german syntax trees are currently being adapted to English.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.32">These also contribute information to the synthesis module in order to achieve better pronunciation.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.33">The current english version is probably the best working one, since some of the problems with the original system have been corrected.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed010.s.34">The design of the belief-net has also progressed significantly: the vast majority of the nodes have been identified and the feasibility of the task from a technical point of view has been confirmed.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>