<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bed016.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.1">The meeting was taken up by discussion about a thesis proposal and a talk about to take place at EML.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.2">The latter will present the work that is currently being done at ICSI including examples of inference of user intentions and of the recordings of the on-going data collection.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.3">The talk will also outline the theoretical (X-schemas, image schemas, Bayes-nets) and neural background.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.4">The thesis proposal, on the other hand, presents the idea of "construal" and makes claims as to how inferences are drawn in a probabilistic relational model by using information from the ontology, situation, user and discourse models.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.5">It was advised that more emphasis should be put on the role of construal in the understanding of metaphor and metonymy.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.6">Base constructions deal with the norm, while further general domain mechanisms determine how the constructions are invoked depending on the context.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.7">Several potential examples of polysemy were discussed in detail: "walk/run into", "on the bus", "out of film", "where is X?".</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.8">However, none of them was an example of lexical polysemy resolved by construal straightforward enough to include in the proposal; the tourist domain is not metaphor rich.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bed016.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.9">As the talk at EML will also refer to a theoretical framework, it was suggested that along with presenting NTL and the piece on mirror neurons, it also alludes to relevant fMRI work.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.10">The neural side of the research could be of interest to various groups.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.11">The language analysis itself will be introduced in terms of image schemas.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.12">On the other hand, it was arranged for more feedback on the thesis proposal to be sent by email.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.13">The latest version of the construction formalism will also be needed to complete the presentation.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bed016.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.14">It was noted that the thesis proposal did not put any emphasis on metaphor or on the scalability achieved by combining constructions with general construal mechanisms: constructions cover base cases, while metaphoric and metonymic cases are resolved with the extra help provided by construal.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.15">During this discussion, however, the suggested examples of polysemy, which is tackled by the proposed framework, were not straightforward enough.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.16">It was agreed that metaphors are not abundant in the spatial domain.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.17">Some of the candidates discussed were phrases like "on the bus", "out of film", non-spatial uses of "where" or other fixed expressions.</sentence>
</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bed016.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.18">The thesis proposal focuses on how construal works in the tourist domain.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.19">One can build a probabilistic relational model with domain general rules that define how ontology, situation, user and discourse models combine to infer intentions.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.20">The talk for EML includes a presentation of the motivation behind the project, as well as the work already done on SmartKom (parser, generator, synthesis).</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.21">Furthermore, the data collection currently taking place and some preliminary observations are going to be outlined.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed016.s.22">All this is going to be given from the perspective of the general theoretical framework, NTL, with further explanations on X-schemas and also the embodied simulation approach.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>