<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bed012.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.1">The focus of the meeting was on a presentation of the work done already on the building of the Bayes-net.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.2">The input layer deriving information from things like the user and situation models, feeds into a set of decision nodes, such as the Enter/View/Approach (EVA) endpoint.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.3">In any particular situation, most of the outputs will not be relevant to the given context.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.4">Therefore, they will either have to be pruned a posteriori, or only a subset of the possible decision nodes will be computed in each occasion.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.5">The latter option could could follow a binary search-tree approach and it could also be better in computational terms.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.6">In any case, on what basis the "winner" output is chosen is not clear.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.7">One suggestion was discussed: the particular constructions used can determine the pertinent decision (output) nodes.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.8">The complete prototype of the Bayes-net will be presented in the next meeting.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.9">After that, it will be possible to define interfaces and a dummy construction parser, in order to test and link modules together.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bed012.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.10">The suggestion that the most appropriate decision node of the belief-net in each situation could be chosen as a function of what construction was used, was deemed unsuitable at this stage.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.11">There are many interdependencies between the output nodes that this approach could not take into account.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.12">The rest of the values for the Bayes-net nodes will be built in within the week.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.13">The finished prototype will be presented during the next meeting.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bed012.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.14">Any set of inputs will provide either the whole range of output values of the Bayes-net or an a priori selection of those outputs.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.15">In both cases, what is needed is a way to single out the appropriate outputs for any given context.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.16">For example, in the case of a "where is" question, whether the prevalent output should be "Go-there" or "Info-on" or even a third option has to be computed somehow.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.17">In any case, there are many input values that have not been entered in the Bayes-net at this stage.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.18">Furthermore, no inputs for the Ontology and Discourse can be built in yet, as they involve research that will be carried out in the future.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.19">Finally, there has been a problem with adding probabilities in a net created with the Hugin software, but this should be overcome very shortly.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bed012.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.20">The presented Bayes-net takes inputs from the Situation, User, Discourse and Ontology models.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.21">There are several values (elements) defined in each of these models.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.22">The inputs are fed into the belief-net, which, in turn, outputs the posterior probabilities for the values of all the decision nodes.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.23">These comprise "Go-there", "EVA", "Info-on", "Location", "Timing", etc.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.24">At this stage, all the decision nodes are evenly weighted: regardless of the context, each output is trusted equally.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.25">Input and output node structure was presented in XML, as this is the format that will be used for the system.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bed012.s.26">A large number of the value probabilities have already been set.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>