<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bmr026.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.1">This is a relatively short meeting of the Meeting Recorder group, with only a few agenda items.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.2">Transcription was discussed briefly because Jane was not present, however this appears to be progressing well in parallel with IBM.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.3">Web pages have been set up to show transcription status and to allow participants to approve transcripts.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.4">DARPA demos are progressing well with the back-end indexed to allow front-end filtering, and a potential demo ideas investigated which would use X Waves.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.5">Transcriber is now working for Windows, however live pitch contours may not work in the time available.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.6">Backed-up disk space is now fine, however temporary space is running out fast.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.7">Interim measures are discussed while sysadmin are away.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.8">Improvement has been made in the final version of the PLP, which shows better female performance, and combined with Mel Ceptra offers 1.5% improvement.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.9">Digit performance also improved thanks to training using scripted speech data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.10">Progress has also been made in SRI alignment for tandem system.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.11">The group note that the annual report needs to be worked on for next week, and it is also suggested to hold recognition meetings separately, however these issues will be discussed in more detail at the next meeting.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bmr026.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.12">Jane will be contacted to see whether transcribers could work on a small amount of SmartKom data, in order to get the project moving.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.13">Details of the transcription status web page will be sent to the group.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.14">Participants will be contacted to approve transcripts or suggest edits, however this depends upon decisions regarding disk space and (un)compression of audio files.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.15">There are disk space problems regarding scratch space, although the group decide that a solution about adding extra drives cannot be resolved without talking to sysadmin.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.16">Until they can be contacted, the group will use the hard drives on each other's machines.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.17">Displaying pitch contours live in Transcriber would be desirable for the demo, however, if the group run out of time, the group note that they could generate this statically using Powerpoint.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.18">The group decide that it may be more beneficial to have separate meetings to discuss recognition, since Jane and Liz are less likely to be interested in this.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.19">They will discuss this with them before going ahead.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bmr026.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.20">Scratch disk space used to store the uncompressed meetings when they are being processed is getting short - the group are using 98%.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.21">Various options are suggested about adding extra drives, externally to their machines, or to the server, but these cannot be resolved until after the relevant sysadmin person returns from a break in 10 days time.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.22">Time is getting tight for some of the demo development, especially a lack of Tcl-TK skills slowing up back-end progress.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.23">Additionally, time constraints may impinge upon the "live-ness" of the Transcriber pitch contour demo.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.24">Annual report is due next week, so this will need to be discussed at the next meeting.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bmr026.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.25">The group are still waiting for IBM to return transcripts next week.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.26">This is not holding the group up, since parallel transcription is being used, and new transcribers have been recruited.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.27">The web page detailing transcription status is working and being updated when possible.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.28">Backed-up disk space has been seen as a priority by sysadmin, and the group are now only using 30% of this.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.29">DARPA demos are progressing, with indexing added to the back-end, which will allow the front end to do filtering.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.30">Transcriber has been developed to run on a Windows machine, with further development being undertaken to add a pitch contour display.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.31">There is also the potential for a demo to be developed from X Waves.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.32">The final version of PLP has been tested which shows similar performance as the system with the Mel Ceptra front-end (although performance for males is slightly, but non-significantly better).</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.33">Combining the two systems gives a 1.5% improvement in performance.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.34">There has also been some improvement with digits, by training the system on read speech data, rather than training solely on TI digits or TIMIT data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr026.s.35">Progress is being made with SRI system alignment, with label files converted to train the net.</sentence> 

</progress>
</nite:root>