<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bmr013.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.1">The Berkeley Meeting Recorder group discussed the collection status for a set of connected digits recordings that are nearly complete and ready to be trained on a recognizer.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.2">Anticipated results were discussed in reference to results obtained for other digits corpora, i.e. Aurora and TI-digits.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.3">The group also considered the prospect of performing fine-grained acoustic-phonetic analyses on a subset of Meeting Recorder digits or Switchboard data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.4">Pre-segmentation manipulations that allow for the segmentation of channel-specific speech/non-speech portions of the signal and the distinction of foreground versus background speech were discussed.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.5">Finally, speaker fe008 and fe016 reported on new efforts to adapt transcriptions to the needs of the SRI recognizer, including conventions for encoding acronyms, numbers, ambient noise, and unidentified inbreaths.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bmr013.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.6">The group decided to delegate the extraction of digits to the transcriber pool.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.7">A tentative decision was also made to delegate transcribers with the task of labelling a subset of digits or Switchboard data for fine-grained acoustic-phonetic features.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.8">Speaker fe008 will run selected Meeting Recorder data through channelize and determine whether the resulting units are of a sufficient length.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bmr013.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.9">With respect to encoding more fine-grained acoustic information in transcriptions, the question was posed: which features should be marked?</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.10">Speaker mn014 reported problems pre-segmenting speech recorded via the lapel microphones.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.11">Normalization of the energy measured across and within channels is problematic when performed for speakers who say little or nothing during meetings.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.12">The evaluation of pre-segmented data is difficult without tightly transcribed time references to the individual channels from which the speech was derived.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.13">The SRI recognizer requires that multi-channel format units not be too large, indicating that some additional pre-processing of unit lengths may be necessary.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bmr013.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.14">A test set of Meeting Recorder digits is nearly complete.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.15">Future work will include training this data on a recognizer, and feeding the recognizer with corresponding far-field microphone data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.16">It was noted that the results of experiments testing similar digits corpora have yielded high error rates, indicating that similar problems may be expected for the set of Meeting Recoreder digits.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.17">The group discussed the prospect of performing fine-grained acoustic-phonetic analyses on a subset of digits or Switchboard data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.18">It was suggested that prior to the use of data-driven methods, knowledge-driven approaches should be used to 'seed' the data with sub-phonemic features, either manually, or using a rich pronunciation dictionary.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.19">A new version of the pre-segmentation tool that segments channel-specific speech/non-speech portions of the signal has been developed and tested.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.20">Future pre-segmentation work will include normalizing other features, such as loudness, enabling the distinction of foreground versus background speech.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.21">Speaker mn014 will also look at cross-correlations for removing false overlaps.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.22">New efforts were reported to adapt transcriptions to the needs of the SRI recognizer, including conventions for encoding acronyms, numbers, ambient noise, and unidentified inbreaths.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr013.s.23">With the arrival of the SRI recognizer, 12 hours of forced aligned, recognized data can be expected.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>