<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bmr003.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.1">The Berkeley Meeting Recorder group discussed the aims, methods, timing, and outsourcing issues concerning transcription of the Meeting Recorder corpus.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.2">The Transcriber software tool was introduced, along with a set of transcription conventions for coding different speech events.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.3">The prospect of sending the data to an external transcription service was weighed against that of hiring a graduate student transcriber pool.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.4">It was tentatively decided that the latter option would be less costly and allow BMR to maintain greater control over the transcription process.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.5">Methods for distributing the data were briefly discussed, along with an initiative for creating a BMR project website.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.6">The group received an update on the meeting room recording setup and electronics.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bmr003.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.7">The group will obtain a copy of the Corpus of Spoken American English (CSAE) from the LDC to compare the methods and conventions used by UC Santa Barbara with those being considered for the Meeting Recorder project.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.8">Speakers fe008 and me011 will experiment with pre-segmentation procedures in hopes of facilitating the transcription process.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.9">Speaker fe008 will perform the transcription for one meeting (40-60 minutes of data) as a pilot project.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.10">A tentative decision was made to put speaker fe008 in charge of the in-house transcription effort.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.11">Modifications to the Transcriber source code, e.g. adjusting the delay between the audio play function and the inputting of time boundaries, may be undertaken by the BMR group.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.12">An initiative for creating an internal BMR project website was discussed, along with ideas for providing web access to external organizations, such as the University of Washington.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.13">A cabinet will be built to house wires and other electronic equipment used in the recording setup.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.14">A laptop and wireless modem will be avaiable to participants for monitoring the recording progress.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bmr003.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.15">How should transcripts and corresponding audio files be formatted and distributed?</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.16">External transcription services are expensive, difficult to monitor, and are unlikely to be able to handle multi-channel data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.17">It is unclear which levels of transcription should be encoded.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.18">What size of segment is most useful for doing transcriptions?</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.19">Which level of segmentation is most suitable for the aims of the project?</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.20">Transcriber's interface only allows the user to view two overlapping speakers.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.21">Decisions must be made regarding the security of electronic recording equipment.</sentence>
</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bmr003.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.22">Efforts are in progress to collect and transcribe 30-40 hours of Meeting Recorder data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.23">The Transcriber tool is being used to do word-level transcriptions, and was reported to work well, when used with supplementary scripts, for specifying multiple speakers.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.24">Other levels of transcription being considered include marking stress, repairs, and false starts.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.25">A set of transcription conventions have been formulated for marking colloquial forms, the continuity of utterances, etc.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.26">A cost assessment was made for sending Meeting Recorder data to an external transcription service.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.27">It was agreed that hiring linguistics graduate students would be cheaper and allow the group to maintain greater control over the transcription process.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.28">Tentative pre-segmentation efforts will enable the automatic generation of phrase boundaries and speaker identity coding, and will be extendable for use at UW.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.29">Perl and XWaves scripts are available for extracting and aligning digits data.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.30">Other suggestions for future work included performing multi-channel speech/non-speech detection, and linking an ASR system to the Transcriber tool.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.31">The recording room electronics setup has been diagrammed and will take approximately one week to configure.</sentence> <sentence nite:id="Bmr003.s.32">It was suggested that such efforts will enable researchers at UW and other collaborating institutions to create their own recording setups more cheaply.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>