<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bro004.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.1">The meeting was dominated by a discussion of the first results coming
in.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.2">There have been four types of test, in which the training data
varies, and a variety of input features have been tried.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.3">The process
and results were explained to the group, the implications of the
results discussed, and plans for moving forward were made.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.4">There was also discussion of some of the work being conducted by
research partners OGI, including how the two groups should best work
together.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.5">The group also briefly touched upon resource issues.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bro004.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.6">Speaker mn007 would like to investigate increasing the context of the
phonemes.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.7">speaker mn013 does agree with mn007s assessment of the
outcome, and points out the lack of data, but acknowledges that if
mn007 is interested he will go ahead with it.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.8">Must be careful in choosing which experiments to perform as an
important visitor is coming soon.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.9">Also need to come up with a
stronger plan for collaboration with OGI.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.10">Must decide what from both
can be brought together, and how then can the work be divided.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.11">Someone (implied with gestures in the meeting) must speak to a person
outside the group with regards to using a multiprocessor Linux machine
that is available.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.12">Debugging the process while there are just two
processors bodes well for when they have 8 to multi-thread.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.13">Speaker mn026 volunteers to get some training running under Linux.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.14">It
is agreed that he should start with the neural net training, then work
on HTK.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bro004.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.15">Incorrect assumptions were made when considering the on-line
normalization for the main task.  members used different values to a
previous study, and whilst it was believed not to make a difference,
it does, so networks are being retrained.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.16">Currently working with noise conditions being the same in training and
test data, but there is nothing which matches the noise on the Italian
test data.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.17">In fact no other language matches the noise from Aurora
data.</sentence> 
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.18">Spanish was being used to train for Italian as it was assumed they
were the most similar, but that may not be as close a match as
thought.</sentence>  
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.19">OGI have an interesting approach to Voice Activation Detection for
removing blocks of silence, that shows good results, but currently the
word model being used is too poor to make good use of this and no one
is working on improving it.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bro004.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.20">Speakers mn007 and fn002 have been running experiments.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.21">Looking at
different features, under different training conditions.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.22">Moving from
training with task data to broad data increases error rate by 10%, and
moving to multiple languages increases a further 20-30%.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.23">PLP with
JRASTA better than just PLP on mismatched conditions, but slightly
worse on well matched.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.24">Speaker fn002 is also looking at the HTK training, but does not yet
have results.</sentence>
<sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.25">Speaker mn007 is going to start work on creating broad phonetic
categories based on various features, and combine this with original
features like PLP.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro004.s.26">As yet unsure how to combine the data however.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>