<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bro008.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.1">The Berkley Meeting Recorder Group discussed the most recent progress with their current project, a digit recognition system for use in cell phones.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.2">This included some discussion of results, comparing various other groups' systems, issues involving the set up, and plans for future work.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bro008.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.3">Results are required for an upcoming meeting, but since some group members will be away, results need to be in sooner.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bro008.problems.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.4">Although error rates have been greatly reduced, current rates are still unusable in a practical situation.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.5">There is a problem replicating some results found by partner OGI, but it is unclear why.</sentence>

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bro008.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.6">mn007 and fn002 have been working with the new Danish and German databases, making improvements, though more so with results on the Danish.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.7">The results are reasonable, but still not good enough.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.8">However, it has not been possible to compare results to the best, as still development system.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.9">There are a number of things that the group wishes to consider for looking for further improvements.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.10">There are various techniques that various groups have tried, and they should all be considered for possible combinations of systems.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro008.s.11">One suitable candidate for combination is the group's own filtering which reduces bandwidth to half bit transmission rate.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>