<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" standalone="yes"?>
<nite:root xmlns:nite="http://nite.sourceforge.net/">
<abstract nite:id="Bro019.abstract.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.1">The ICSI Meeting Recorder Group at Berkley have a temporary new member on loan from research partner OGI.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.2">He began the meeting by reporting his recent activities, which included looking at the new baseline system.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.3">The other members of the group also reported their recent progress in areas such as spectral subtraction and voicing detection.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.4">They also explained some of their projects to their guest.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.5">The group shall soon be taking delivery of more machines for a computation farm, and they discussed some software tools for running large processes.</sentence>

</abstract>
<decisions nite:id="Bro019.decisions.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.6">Speaker me018 will construct an FAQ about the new computing tools and setup, and email details.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.7">Fn002 agrees to try an alternative approach to her new feature for voicing detection.</sentence>

</decisions>
<problems nite:id="Bro019.problems.1">
blank

</problems>
<progress nite:id="Bro019.progress.1">
<sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.8">Speaker mn007 has taken the spectral subtraction from another groups system, and is trying it with their own, with mixed results.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.9">He is also looking into alternative methods of removing noise.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.10">Fn002 is still working on voicing detection, and has run experiments with her new feature with disappointing results.</sentence>  <sentence nite:id="Bro019.s.11">Though not directly related to the groups work, speaker me006 has been putting together his proposal or a PhD, and me026 has been helping another researcher with his work on formants.</sentence>

</progress>
</nite:root>